SUMMARY OF SKILLS

Programming knowledge in C, C#, C++, Java, Python, Perl, SQL, MongoDB, HTML, JavaScript, LISP, Prolog, PHP and R

Experienced in working with ${\bf Rosetta}$ protein modeling suite

Experienced in working in GxP, and FDA regulated environments

Experienced in working with Git, SVN, and Mercurial version control systems

Experienced in working in **Windows** and **Unix** environments Effective presenter, communicator, writer, and public speaker Efficient at coordinating across multiple groups for requirements

Strong independent and autodidactic worker

EDUCATION

Ramapo College of New Jersey – Mahwah, NJ

Bachelor of Science: Bioinformatics, May 2016, *Magna cum laude* Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, May 2016, *Magna cum laude*

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pfizer Inc. - Pearl River, NY

Senior System Analyst, Research Informatics, Dec. 2018– Current System Analyst, Research Informatics, Jan. 2017 – Dec 2018

Support Vaccines R&D laboratories by through developing, supporting, and validating applications

- Develop and design systems to manage, analyze, and report laboratory data in our Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS)
- Create and provide ad hoc reports in Oracle Database using SQL
- Perform benchmarks on system performance and follow up to optimize problematic processes
- Design and create tools to visualize and prioritize the Research Informatics support ticket queue using **Java** and **JavaScript**, with rapid prototyping using **PHP**
- Coordinating multiple laboratory groups to gather requirements for new assay systems
- Provide end user support for clients using Research Informatics systems
- Validate and document newly deployed/changed/upgraded systems and environments

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

A Bioinformatic Approach to Investigate a Relationship between Cis-Regulatory U-Rich and G-quadruplex Motifs Involved in Mammalian Polyadenylation

School of Theoretical and Applied Sciences – Ramapo College of New Jersey Undergraduate Researcher, Jan. 2014 – July 2016

Developed genome-wide analysis tools using Java, JavaScript, C++, and Python

- Web service with a C++ backend and Python database access, on a Node.js webserver
- Performed programmatic alignments of sequence data using Needleman-Wunsch algorithm
- Extracted and stored nucleic acid sequence data and annotations using MongoDB
- Presented research project at Student Research Symposium, MACUB conference, and RNA Conference 2016

Marburg Virus Antibody Modeling using Comparative Modeling

Center for Structural Biology – Vanderbilt University & RosettaCommons Developer of Rosetta, powerful macromolecule structure prediction and design software Research Intern, May. 2015 – Aug. 2015

NSF funded research internship through RosettaCommons

- Trained to understand Rosetta protein modeling suite and develop algorithms for protein folding
- Developed a protocol for efficient large scale comparative modeling of antibodies
- Accesses underlying Rosetta C++functions for modeling, XML for input of user parameters
- Integration with PyMOL using Python
- Increased automation using Perl and Bash scripts
- Benchmarked the efficacy of comparative modeling techniques
- Presented Research at RosettaCON